jcpenneyoptical.com 2018-05-05

# privacy policy - JCPenney

###  **J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc.  Privacy Policy (rev. 08/01/17) **

The following Privacy Policy applies to information collected by J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc. its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “JCPenney,” “we” or “us”) in the United States and Puerto Rico at JCPenney’s retail stores and through our websites and mobile applications.

###  table of contents 

  * information we collect
  * using the information we collect
  * information we share with others
  * safeguarding the Information we collect
  * your choices about how we use information
  * opt-outs for interest-based advertising (IBA)
  * our use of cookies and other technologies 
  * links to other sites and social media widgets
  * children’s privacy
  * notice to California residents – your California privacy rights  
  * international customer privacy
  * changes to this policy

###  **information we collect**

We collect information from various sources: from you, through your transactions during visits to our stores or websites, your use of our mobile applications, or your use of in-store guest Wi-Fi service; from your computer and mobile devices; from third-party sources; and from public sources.

When you interact with JCPenney, we collect information, including personal information, from you. Personal information is information that can be used or combined to identify you. For example, we may collect your:

• name;

• address(es) (for shipping and billing);

• email address(es);

• telephone/mobile phone number;

• credit/debit card number;

• checking account information;

• driver’s license number;

• digital image, if captured via security cameras;

• location information; and

• social media information. (e.g. handle or ID, gender, age)

###  **when we collect your information**

Such information can be collected, for instance, when:

• you make a purchase, return or exchange;

• you create/use an account on one of our websites (e.g. jcp.com, jcprewards.com, etc.);

• you sign up to receive coupons, sales alerts and promotional emails, or text messages;

• you join a loyalty program (e.g. JCPenney Rewards) or club;

• you participate in a contest, sweepstakes, promotion, survey or consumer research;

• you create or update a gift registry, or a save for later list;

• you submit a rating or review, or other user-generated content that may be posted to our website;

• you request customer service or contact us;

• you apply for or use a JCPenney Credit Card;

• you engage with JCPenney  on social media sites (e.g. Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, etc.);

• you view or click on a JCPenney advertisement;

• you enable location-based functionalities through your computer/mobile device, or when using the JCPenney mobile application;

• you use the scan ID/credit card functionality of the JCPenney mobile application or the mobile website;

• you use our in-store Wi-Fi network; or

• you ask us to ship an order to a gift recipient.

**information from your computer/mobile device  **– We and our third-party service providers may automatically collect information from your device when you visit our websites, use our mobile applications, or use our in-store guest Wi-Fi service. This information helps us improve your shopping experience, while helping us learn more about our customers, and assist with fraud prevention.  We and our service providers may automatically collect such data as:

• type of device and device manufacturer;

• your device’s internet service provider, connection speed, and internet protocol (IP) address;

• device operating system,  and browser type, browser language, any plug-ins that you have installed on your browser;

• cookie information;

• the date;

• if online, click-stream data -  the website you came from, those you visit, and the items you click on during your session;

• information about Javascript objects on particular screens;

• the number of mouse clicks made on particular screens (or touches, if using a touch-screen device);

• if you consent, precise, real-time location information; 

• any unique device IDs and any unique IDs associated with advertising and analytics; 

• if using the mobile application scanning feature: time stamps, bar code or other information; and

• information about the way you use our mobile applications.

If you consent to using in-store guest Wi-Fi service, we automatically collect:

o    usage data (e.g. number of users by store, the websites visited while using the service);

o    session data (e.g. how long a user stays on the guest Wi-Fi service), device and browser data (e.g. type of device, device ID, type of browser, IP address); and

o    precise, real-time information about the location of your device. 

In addition, if you consent, we may also collect precise location information (using GPS, Wi-Fi, or cell tower triangulation, or a combination of these technologies) when you use our mobile applications.

**information from third-party sources** \- We may receive information about you from third-parties. For example, if you have a JCPenney Credit Card, we receive application and account information from the credit card issuing bank. We also obtain data from third parties to improve the accuracy of and add to what we know about our customers. This may improve the relevance of the offers or product recommendations we provide you or enhance our ability to contact you. For example, we may work with other websites and services to present advertising to groups of our customers when they visit those sites. Non-personal data received by us from this process is used to analyze the effectiveness of such advertising.

**publicly available information** –  We may collect information about you that is publicly available. For example, information you submit in a public forum (e.g. a blog, chat room or social network) can be read, collected or used by us or others, and could be used to personalize your experience.

###  **using the information we collect**

We use the information we collect to offer, improve, and provide our products and services, and to carry out various business functions. We may combine, or use the services of third party companies to combine information about you that we collect online, in our stores, through mobile applications, and from third-party and public sources.  Examples of how that information is used include:

• to communicate with you about and complete purchase, return or exchange transactions;

• to provide or communicate with you about products or services;

• for marketing and promotional purposes, including direct mail, coupons, emails, mobile alerts, and serving advertisements;

• to provide interactive features of our websites and mobile applications, such as product ratings and reviews, share with a friend, find item in store, store ads, push notifications and store locator;

• to improve your in-store experience in conjunction with our use of wireless beacons;

• to provide proximity-based features to customers, such as advertising  and “buy online, pick-up in store;”

• to identify product and service preferences, so we can inform our customers and visitors of new or additional products, services and promotions of possible interest;

• to improve our websites, stores, mobile applications, customer service, and marketing efforts;

• to connect, enhance, and personalize our customers shopping experience across channels and devices;

• to pre-populate customer information within our websites and mobile application;

• to administer loyalty programs, contests, sweepstakes, promotions, surveys, and focus groups;

• to conduct research and analysis and perform other business activities as needed;

• to protect the security and integrity of our websites and our business; and

• to monitor against theft, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions, assist law enforcement, and respond to legal/regulatory inquiries.

As noted above, we may use the information we collect and receive to personalize your JCPenney experience across channels. We may combine information to link your activity through one channel to your activity in another, such as linking information from your in-store activity to your activity on our websites, or linking your activity from one device to another, such as from a mobile device and a laptop computer. Personalization allows JCPenney to target our advertisements and communications to deliver more relevant content to you based on how you interact with us. To accomplish personalization, we use first- and third-party technologies (cookies, web beacons, etc.) to collect and share this information, as described in other sections of this notice. To opt-out of the third-party technologies used for personalization, see the "opt-outs for interest-based advertising (IBA)" section of this notice below.

###  **information we share with others**

**JCPenney family** \- We share information we collect with affiliated companies and licensees (e.g. the optical and photography departments in our stores) within the JCPenney family of businesses.

**service providers** \- We disclose or otherwise make available information we collect with other companies that help with our business operations.  Examples include providers of services related to e-mail communications, mobile marketing, analytics, product fulfillment, and web hosting; payment processors; or entities that help us market our products and services. In addition, we use third-parties to assist with fraud detection and to validate aspects of customer transactions. 

**third-party marketing** \- We may provide information about you to third-party companies or organizations.  These entities may use that information to market their products and services to you. To opt-out of such sharing, go to the "your choice about how we use information" section of this policy.

**registry partners** \- If you create a gift registry, we will share your event information with our gift registry partners, and your event information will be accessible on our websites, through our mobile applications and in our stores.

**legal or safety requirements** \- We may disclose information we collect when we believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law; to enforce or apply applicable terms and conditions and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of our business, our customers or others.

**business transfers** \- If the ownership of JCPenney or all or part of a business within the JCPenney family were to change, information about customers pertinent to JCPenney or that business’s operations would likely be transferred to, or licensed for use by, the new owner.  The applicable member of the JCPenney family might also retain a copy of that information.

**sharing aggregate Information** \- We may share aggregate information (information that does not directly identify any individual) with third parties for lawful purposes.

###  **safeguarding the information we collect**

We have physical, technical and procedural safeguards in place to protect the personal information we collect. We use industry standard technology to encrypt your credit or debit card information, including the account number, while it is transmitted over the internet from your computer.  We also require service providers to have safeguards in place to protect the personal information that they collect, use, share, and store on our behalf.

**your choices about how we use information**

**updating your JCPenney contact information and preferences**

If you have created a jcpenney.com account or a gift registry account/profile, you can update your information by signing back into your account or registry.  Or, to update or correct your name, address, telephone number, or email address, you may:

• email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com),

• call us at 1.800.322.1189, or

•  write to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Care.

Customers may also exercise their preferences by:

• accessing their information through their jcpenney.com account, or

• responding to messages according to the opt-out instructions provided therein.

**opt-outs for postal mail and email**

If you do not want to receive coupons and other promotional mail, or if you do not want to receive promotional email offers and updates from JCPenney, you may:

• email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com),

• call us at 1.800.322.1189, or

• write to us at J.C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX. 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Care.

You may also opt-out of promotional email offers and updates from JCPenney at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” hyperlink contained in our promotional emails. If you have registered on jcpenney.com, you can cancel your email subscription through your account.

Please note that even if you unsubscribe from promotional email offers and updates, we may still contact you by email for transactional purposes.  Some examples are communications regarding your order status, JCPenney Rewards if you are a member, customer service inquiries, service or reminder notices, and product recalls.

  **opt-out for JCPenney mobile marketing messages**

If you are currently receiving promotional text alerts from JCPenney, you may unsubscribe at any time by texting **STOP** to 527365. After we receive your opt-out, we will send you a final text message to confirm the opt-out.  You may also:

• email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com),

• call us at 1.800.322.1189, or

• write to us at J.C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX. 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Care.

**opt-out for JCPenney transactional SMS (text) messages**

If you are currently receiving text alerts from JCPenney, you may unsubscribe at any time by texting **STOP** to 65566. After we receive your opt-out, we will send you a final text message to confirm the opt-out.  You may also:

• email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com),

• call us at 1.800.322.1189, or

• write to us at J.C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX. 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Care.

  **opt-out of sharing with other companies for their marketing purposes**

If you do not want JCPenney to share information about you with companies outside the JCPenney family for their marketing purposes, you may stop such sharing by:

• emailing us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com),

• calling us at 1.800.322.1189, or

• writing to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Care.

**opt-out of location information collection**

If you do not want JCPenney to collect real-time location information from your device, you may opt-out of such collection as follows:

• for jcpenney.com: deny permission when asked if the website can track your physical location. To opt-out after initial permission is given, adjust your browser settings.

• for JCPenney’s mobile application: adjust the permission settings for your device, or uninstall the application.

• for JCPenney’s mobile website: deny permission when asked if the website can track your physical location.

• for JCPenney’s in-store Wi-Fi service: collection of precise location information is automatic, to prevent this collection, refrain from using our in store guest wi-fi service.

**opt-outs for certain third-party services**

JCPenney uses third-party analytics companies on its websites and mobile applications. For more on JCPenney’s use of third-parties for analytics, see "our use of cookies and other technologies" below and review the "analytics services" section.

_Google Analytics_

•         To learn more about Google Analytics’ privacy practices and any opt-out choices it offers, [click here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).

_Adobe Analytics_

•         To learn more about Adobe Analytics’ privacy practices or to opt-out of cookies set to facilitate reporting by Adobe Analytics, [click here](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html).

Please note that your opt-out status may be maintained by placement of an “opt-out” cookie on your device.  If the cookie is removed or deleted, or you upgrade to a new version of your browser, change browsers or visit us from a different device, you will need to repeat this process to indicate your preference.

**opt-outs for interest-based advertising (IBA)**

As noted above in the “using the information we collect” section of this notice, we collect, combine, and share information to personalize your JCPenney experience across channels and across devices to target our communications and advertising. We allow third-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our site and we use third-party advertising companies to serve ads (e.g. banners or links) on our behalf across the internet and mobile applications that are tailored to your individual interests. For more information on JCPenney’s use of ad technology, see "technology used to serve advertising" below.

**website IBA**

To learn more about interest-based advertising or to “opt-out” of interest based advertising programs from participating companies:

• visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>, or

• visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

These opt-outs limit the sharing of information from the devices and browsers for which the opt-out is in effect. To maximize your control over IBA and cross-device tracking, you may choose to exercise this opt-out choice using each browser on each device that you use to interact with us. Please note that the opt-outs you make on one or both of those websites only apply to the receipt of interest-based advertising from participating third-party companies.  You may still receive other types of online advertising from participating companies, and the websites you visit may still collect information for other purposes.

Also, your opt-out status may be maintained by placement of an “opt-out” cookie on your computer.  If the cookie is removed or deleted, you upgrade to a new version of your browser, change browsers, or visit us from a different computer or device, you will need to repeat this process to indicate your opt-out preference.

**mobile application IBA**

To exercise choice for mobile applications on mobile devices, you may download the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA’s) App Choices application from your devices app store. In addition, for some devices, you may exercise choice through your device settings.

###  **our use of cookies and other technologies**

**cookies** \- A cookie is a small data file stored by your web browser on your computer or device. When you arrive at our website, cookies allow us or our third-party service providers to recognize you by an identification number in the cookie. We and our service providers use "cookies" to collect and analyze information about your browsing and buying activity on our site, whether through the Internet or mobile applications. You may use the privacy settings on your web browser to disable cookies. If so, you can still browse our websites, but you may not have as exceptional a shopping experience as one that is specifically tailored to your needs. However, if you block cookies you will not be able to make a purchase on our websites.

**web beacons** \- A “web beacon” (also called a pixel tag or a clear gif) is a tiny graphic image placed on website pages and in emails, advertising, and other marketing communications that allows us and our third-party service providers to determine whether you have performed specific actions. When you access those pages or open email messages, or click on advertising, the web beacons generate a notice of that action to us, or our service providers.  That information is used to analyze what our visitors like to do on our site or mobile applications, and the effectiveness of our features and advertising, as well as interactions with our e-mail and advertising.

**wireless beacons** \- A wireless beacon is a small device that we may use as part of our in-store experience. Wireless beacons broadcast a signal that can be received by compatible devices, such as a mobile phone or tablet, when those devices are within the proximity of the beacon. When you choose to download the JCPenney mobile application, we and our service providers may use wireless beacons in conjunction with the JCPenney mobile application to personalize and enhance your in-store shopping experience and to understand your interests so that we can provide relevant notifications, offers, and promotions.

**flash cookies** – A flash cookie (also known as a Local Shared Object) is a persistent data file stored on your computer by the websites you visit using Adobe Flash technology. We or our service providers may use Flash cookies to enable or control Flash-based content and for other uses similar to those provided by the cookies discussed earlier in this section. You can manage the use of Flash cookies via the Settings Manager on Adobe’s website at <https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>

  **analytics services** \- JCPenney uses third party analytics companies to collect and analyze information about how people use our websites and mobile applications, including information about browsing and buying activities. They may collect and use information from first- and third-party cookies. In addition, analytics companies also provide services that analyze information regarding visits to certain portions of jcpenney.com that are operated for JCPenney by third parties. They use cookies and web beacons to collect this information.

**technology used to serve advertising** \- We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads (e.g. banners or links) tailored to your individual interests based on how you browse and shop on jcpenney.com and other sites over time, and to perform tracking and reporting functions with respect to our ads. We also allow third-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our site and to use that information to serve ads for JCPenney products or services, or the products or services of other companies when you visit our site or other sites. For instance, we and third-party vendors, such as Google and Facebook use first- and third-party cookies, web beacons (a.k.a. pixel tags) and other technologies to collect or receive information from websites to inform, optimize and serve ads based upon a user’s past visits to our website and to report upon how our ad impressions and other ad services are related to jcpenney.com.  We may combine and associate the information we collect through these technologies with other information we have collected from and about you. This collective information may be used, among other things, for interest-based and location-based advertising to personalize your online experience, improve our website, evaluate the effectiveness of our advertising, and to tailor our marketing to you.

  **do not track** \- At this time, we do not respond to browser “do not track” signals, but we do provide you the option to opt-out of interest-based advertising here, as well as the other choices described in the “your choices about how we use information” section of this policy.

###  **links to other sites and social media widgets**

You may navigate to other websites from JCPenney websites.  When you provide personal information at one of those sites, you are subject to that site operator’s privacy policy. We encourage you to read that policy before submitting any personal information.

Our websites and our mobile applications include social media features, for example the Facebook Like button, and Facebook, Google Plus, Interest, and Twitter widgets. Social media features or widgets are either hosted by a third-party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

###  **children's privacy**

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 through our websites or mobile applications.

###  **notice to California residents - your California privacy rights**

Under California law, a California resident with whom JCPenney has an established relationship has the right to request certain information with respect to the types of personal information JCPenney has shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, and the identities of those third parties, within the immediately preceding calendar year, subject to certain exceptions. All requests for such information must be in writing and sent to:  J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX 75301.  Attention: Corporate Customer Care.

This same California law permits JCPenney to provide you, in response to your written request, with a cost-free means to choose not to have your information shared rather than providing the above described information. You may exercise that choice by any of the means described under “opt-out of sharing with other companies for their marketing purposes”.

###  **international customer privacy**

JCPenney has contracted with Borderfree, Inc. (“Borderfree”) to facilitate the sale and fulfillment of online purchases that our customers choose to ship internationally (an “international order”).

When you place an international order, you will submit personal information (e.g. your name, email address, billing address, and shipping address) and other order-related information to JCPenney through and to servers located in the United States.  If you also choose to create a jcpenney.com account, any personal information you provide will also be transferred to JCPenney through and to servers located in the United States.  Please note that United States law may not provide a level of data protection equivalent to the laws in your home country.  This privacy policy applies to any personal information you furnish JCPenney in connection with international orders, your jcpenney.com account or otherwise.

JCPenney will then share your international order information, including personal information about you, with Borderfree for the purpose of facilitating ordering and shipping internationally.  Borderfree will process personal information about you in accordance with its [privacy policy](http://shop.borderfree.com/privacy-policy).  Borderfree has agreed not to sell, transfer, or otherwise use your information other than for processing international orders and shipments.

By placing an international order, you acknowledge and agree that JCPenney will transfer personal information about you to Borderfree, and acknowledge that your financial transaction and shipment will be processed by Borderfree.  During the checkout process, you will be presented with Borderfree’s terms and conditions and privacy policy.  You must agree to them to receive the product(s) you ordered.

Once your order is approved, JCPenney will ship it to Borderfree.  Simultaneously, Borderfree will purchase the product(s) you ordered from us, which allows them to take title to the product(s), bill your credit card, collect and remit any duties and taxes to the appropriate taxing authorities and arrange for the product(s) to be delivered to you.  In this process, Borderfree makes the sale to you as the merchant of record.

Customers shipping internationally should email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com) if they wish to:

• inquire about or update their personal information,

• make a complaint about the collection or use of their personal information, or

• comment on or ask questions regarding JCPenney’s privacy policy,

###  **changes to this policy**

This policy was last updated on August 1, 2017.and included the following changes:

• Added the “opts-out for interest-based advertising (IBA)” heading to the Table of Contents and added a hyperlink to that section.

• Revised the “information we collect” section to include social media information as an example and to generalize the reference to location information.

• Revised the “when we collect your information” section to include advertisements as an example.

• Revised the “information from your computer/mobile device” section to better describe the purposes of device information collection, add types of information that may be collected from devices, and add language about precise location information methodologies.

• Revised the “using the information we collect” section to provide additional explanation about our use of information for cross-channel and cross device personalization.

• Revised the “information we share with others” section to more clearly describe purposes of information sharing with third-parties.

• Updated the “safeguarding the information we collect” section to remove references to any specific technology.

• Added hyperlinks to the “opt-outs for certain third-party services” section and removed the opt-out for IBM Digital Analytics.

• Revised and renamed the “opt-outs for interest-based advertising (IBA) section to include the mobile application opt-out information and link and to separate it from the opt-out for websites. Also included additional explanation of the website IBA opt-out.

• Added hyperlink to the “flash cookies” section.

• Updated the “technology used to serve advertising” section to include references to specific third-parties and explain uses of these technologies.

• Added a “do not track” section with the “do not track” language previously included in the “technology used to serve advertising” section.

We may change our privacy policy from time to time.  If we change our privacy policy in the future, we will let you know by posting the updated policy at this website. We encourage you to check our policy periodically. You can tell if it has changed by checking the revision date that appears at the beginning of the policy. If you would like further information, or have any questions about our privacy policy, please:

•         email us at [privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com](mailto:privacy@jcpenneyeservices.com),

•         call us at 1.800.322.1189, or

•         write to us at J. C. Penney Corporation, Inc., P.O. Box 10001, Dallas, TX. 75301-7311, Attention: Corporate Customer Care.
